

# **Andreas Runge**

**General Manager** 

Franz-Wirer von Rettenbach Strasse 25/7, 2100 Korneuburg, Austria DOB 09.05.1974, married, 1 daughter

andreas.hans.runge@gmail.com, phone: + 43 677 635 28200

# **Summary**

General Manager with 25+ years international hotel experience. Worked for major brands like Marriott, Millennium, RAMADA, Wyndham and independent hotels such as The Ritz, London and rocksresort, Laax, Switzerland.

Hands-on, creative innovator and people-oriented motivational leader who always drives cost control for GOP improvement. Managed and shared three new hotel openings and two renovation projects. TOP problem solver.

## **Work History**

# since 05 / 2021

# **General Manager**

### VAYA Resort Achensee, Tirol, Austria

4\* Resort Hotel, 76 Appartments and rooms with 248 beds, 2 F&B Outlets, Spa & Swimming Pool

# 10 / 2020 - 04 / 2021

<u>Sabbatical</u> due to Coronavirus pandemic filled with voluntary work for public Covid-19 tests in Austria

# 01 / 2020 - 09 / 2020

# **Cluster General Manager**

#### RAMADA by Wyndham Hotels Karachi, Pakistan

RAMADA PLAZA Airport Karachi Hotel, 5\* City Resort, 228 keys, 6 F&B Outlets, 10 Meeting rooms, Marquee with 1000 pax capacity, spa, gym, outdoor pool, tennis court.

RAMADA KARACHI Creek, 4\* City Centre Hotel, 48 keys, 3 F&B Outlets, 2 ballrooms, gym, massage rooms.

#### Main achievements:

- Introduction of standards and SOP'S in all departments
- Conducted several renovation projects, i.e. installation new shower cabins in all main building rooms
- Completion and implementation of the 2020 Budget and Sales & Marketing plan
- Leadership of a total workforce of 650 staff in both hotels accumulated
- Introduction of Revenue Management with logical pricing structures and online rate parity principles
- Extensive networking and sales penetration of the local market
- Crisis Management after the start of the Coronavirus pandemic in march 2020

# 11 / 2017 - 11 / 2019

## **General Manager**

### RAMADA by Wyndham Hotel Bahrain, Kingdom of Bahrain

4\* City Center Hotel, 123 keys, 4 F&B Outlets, Meeting room, gym & swimming pool

#### Main achievements:

- Conducted several major renovation projects, i.e. installation of sprinkler system, new carpets, new emergency power generator
- NPS increased to 4.3 (Wyndham EMEA average is 3.93)
- Increased occupancy from 58% ( 2017 ) to 69% ( 2018 )

# 11 / 2015 - 10 / 2017

# **General Manager**

### Hawthorn Suites by Wyndham Abu Dhabi City Center, UAE

4\* City Center Hotel, 160 keys, Spa, 8 F&B outlets

#### Main achievements:

- Managing the hotel renovation including rebranding to Wyndham Hotel Group and upgrading from 3 to 4 Star
- Winner of 2016 Best Hotel Renovation EMEA Award Wyndham Hotel Group.
- Implemented Sales & Marketing and Revenue Management strategies, resulting in an increase of occupancy from 57% to 83% (2016 - 2017)
- Increased the service quality in all areas; i.e. raised scoring on booking.com from 6.4 to 8.1
- Decreased the number of staff from 115 to 90 whilst maintaining service levels with multi tasking initiatives and training enhancement.

# 05 / 2012- 10 / 2015

## **General Manager**

### RAMADA Hotels Vienna, Austria (operated by PMT Tourism)

4\* City Center Hotels, 106 & 122 keys, Restaurant, Bar, Conference Center

#### Main achievements:

- General Manager in the flag ship property Ramada Hotel & Suites Vienna.
- Achieved an increase of 23% Revpar in the corporate business segment by aggressive and detailed sales penetration
- Transferred as task force to lead the turn around of the sister properties Ramada Encore and Ramada Vienna South
- **18% growth** of occupancy in the RAMADA Encore in 2014 year to year; resulting in revenue growth of EUR 500K
- Balanced labour turn over to healthy minimum with multi tasking.

# **07 / 2011 - 04 / 2012** (please see education)

# 07 / 2007 - 07 / 2011

### Cluster Hotel Manager (i/c of rooms)

### Weisse Arena Gruppe, Laax, Switzerland

- rocksresort, Resort with 144 appartments, 586 beds, member of design hotels
- signinahotel, 4\* Resort Hotel, 85 keys, 2 F&B outlets, SPA
- Riders Palace, 70 guest rooms, hotel for freestylers

### Main achievements:

- **Structuring of Facility management** and Housekeeping procedures for the appartment and hotel complex (ca. 1000 beds)
- Implemented the **guest relation program** for rocksresort and signinahotel.
- Created innovate features with a WOW effect such as early bird skiing or an Express Check In
- Elaborated excellent relationship with rocksresort appartment owners
- Produced 85% occupancy in the first winter season after opening rocksresort

# 05 | 2004 - 06 | 2007

# Executive Assistant Manager, Rooms Division Manager, FOM

### RAMADA HOTELS SWITZERLAND, Basel & Solothurn

- 01/2007 06/2007 RDM/Ass. GM, RAMADA Solothurn
- 01/2006 01/2007 EAM RAMADA Plaza Basel
- 05 / 2004 12 / 2005 FOM RAMADA Plaza Basel

# 03 / 2002 - 04 / 2004

## **Assistant Front Office Manager**

### Millennium Hotel and Resort, Stuttgart, Germany

4\* Business and Leisure Hotel, 454 keys, Conference Center, 21 F&B outlets, 2 cinemas, casino, musical theatres, extensive spa facilities

# 04 / 2001 - 02 / 2002

### **Reception Manager**

Marriott Hanbury Manor Hotel & Country Club, Ware, Hertfordshire, UK

5\* Country Club Hotel, 161 keys, Conference Center, 5 F&B outlets

# 09 / 2000 - 04 / 2001

### Chef de Brigade

The Ritz, London, UK

5\* Grand Hotel, 161 keys, member of "The Leading Hotel of the world"

# 06 | 1999 - 09 | 2000

### **Night Manager**

Renaissance Düsseldorf Hotel, Germany

5\* Business Hotel, 244 keys, 4 F&B outlets, Conference Center

# 01 / 1998 - 05 / 1999

# **Night Auditor**

Stuttgart Marriott Hotel Sindelfingen, Germany

4\* Business Hotel, 257 keys, 4 F&B outlets, Conference Center

### **Education**

# 07 / 2011 - 04 / 2012

# **Diploma in Hotel Business Administration**

at the IST - Institute in Düsseldorf, Germany

#### Main content:

- Legislation, Corporate management, Hotel administration
- Yield-Management, e-Commerce, Marketing
- Human Resources management, Quality- and customer service management
- F&B and Event management

# 08 | 1995 - 01 | 1998

## **Graduate of the Federal Trade School for Hotel Management**

Hotel School Bad Ueberkingen, Germany and RAMADA Hotel Stuttgart Sindelfingen (dual education)

# 06 / 1994

### **A-Level university-entrance Diploma**

Schickhardt-Gymnasium Herrenberg, Germany

### **Further education:**

Ordinance on aptitude of instructors Wifi Vienna, Austria – July 2014 HOTS Business Simulation (RAMADA) – November 2006 Train the Trainer (RAMADA PLAZA) – July 2005 Fidelio Front Office Supervisor course – Mai 2005

# Further qualifications/languages:

micros fidelio (several versions), micros OPERA, protel

German - mother tongue

English - fluent

French - basic

Austria, July 2021

Andreas Runge